Speaker 1: Last week, one of my favorite sub-stacks, FX Hedgers, did an in-depth review of how the Fed
Speaker 1: broke the housing market. In short, the American dream of home ownership is dying and the Fed
Speaker 1: killed it on behalf of the bozos in Congress. The sordid tale begins with Lyndon B. Johnson
Speaker 1: in the 1960s, who converted a house from something you worked hard to buy into something
Speaker 1: bestowed by government on favored political groups. Johnson began with government money
Speaker 1: for apartments, which the left has always loved since everybody should live in a pod,
Speaker 1: and then single-family homes in poor areas. Of course, this backfired, pricing the poor
Speaker 1: out of the homes they've lived in for generations as prices rose and rents rose, breaking down
Speaker 1: long-standing communities. This took off as inflation sordid in the 1970s, driven by Washington's
Speaker 1: spending for the Vietnam War and Johnson's Great Society welfare program, so-called guns
Speaker 1: and butter. The inflation drove the Fed to hike rates nearly 20%, which finished off many of the
Speaker 1: surviving poor. We got a reprieve in the blockbuster Reagan economy, which allowed wages to catch up
Speaker 1: and made houses affordable again for many Americans, which more or less continued through the 90s,
Speaker 1: at which point it went south. In the name of compassionate conservatism,
Speaker 1: Bush the junior massively expanded government subsidies to housing while effectively forcing
Speaker 1: banks to lend to poor people with bad credit in the name of diversity, while incentivizing ratings
Speaker 1: agencies to look the other way at shell games like reverse amortization partial interest-only
Speaker 1: mortgages, which was actually a product. Of course, this set up the housing crash in 2008 as millions of bad
Speaker 1: loans came due, again throwing millions out of their homes. This set up act two as the Fed responded
Speaker 1: to the housing crisis by forcing interest rates to nearly zero for, it turns out, almost 15 years.
Speaker 1: This drove house prices up again since low rates artificially boost asset values, whether stocks or
Speaker 1: houses. Meanwhile, the Fed also poured gasoline, buying up trillions of mortgage bonds to further
Speaker 1: subsidized mortgages, along with round after round of QE, money printing, in various flavors.
Speaker 1: Now, beyond the zombie economy these low rates delivered, this meant anybody who already owned a home
Speaker 1: had hit the Fed jackpot, while the poor and young were increasingly left behind. They had no homes to
Speaker 1: go up in value. In fact, now they had to buy the expensive homes. In fact, housing is a major driver of that
Speaker 1: income inequality that journalists obsess over. It is not dog-eat-dog capitalism, it is the Fed.
Speaker 1: We got another brief Reagan-style reprieve in the Trump economy as jobs and startups grew, and then of
Speaker 1: course, COVID hit. When the entirety of Washington lost its collective mind, pouring $8 trillion into the
Speaker 1: economy in a desperate attempt to buy the lockdowns the journalists and activists demanded. All of which
Speaker 2: have sent inflation to near double digits, sent home prices soaring again, and drove the Fed to, at this
Speaker 2: point, 8% mortgages that have frozen the entire housing market in amber, since anybody sporting a 3%
Speaker 2: mortgage cannot afford to sell and buy another house at 8. So what's next? Brought to you by Unchained.
Speaker 2: The housing market today is betting on lower rates, but that's not going to do it, because low rates will
Speaker 2: simply prop up home prices and seal the lockout on the young and the poor, while also slowing income
Speaker 2: growth and a repeat of the pre-Trump zombie economy. The end result is what FX Hedgers calls, quote,
Speaker 2: "modern-day serfdom", with the poor and especially the young living hand-to-mouth bystanders to
Speaker 2: Washington's vote-buying circus. Okay, we'll be watching. See you next time.